plenti.com 2018-05-12

# Online Privacy Statement | Plenti

Effective Date: May 4, 2015

Plenti, a rewards program operated by American Express Travel Related Services Company Inc., is committed to respecting your privacy. We want you to know how we may collect, use, share, and keep information about you and the choices that are available to you.

This online privacy statement applies to Plenti websites, online applications that run on smart phones, tablets, and other mobile devices (“apps”) as well as your use or access of any of our online services or content that link to this statement. It does not apply to those websites that have their own online privacy statements such as those of our [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners"). 

Our websites, web services and apps are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly solicit data online from, or market online to, children under 13 years of age. 

Since we may change this online privacy statement, we recommend that you check the current version available from time to time. If we make changes to this statement, we will update the “Effective Date” at the top of this page.

 **What is in this online privacy statement?**

What information does this online privacy statement cover?

What information do we collect online and how do we collect it?

How do we use the information we collect about you?

How do we share your information?

How we treat your Personal Information

How we handle Aggregated Information and De-identified Information

How do we keep and safeguard your information?

What are your choices?

Do you have questions about the online privacy statement?

What information does this online privacy statement cover? 

This online privacy statement describes how we (and our [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers")) may collect, use, share, and keep information that we get about you online. We gather [Online Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Online Information") if you:

• Visit or use our websites, web services or apps;

• Receive or reply to electronic communications from us; 

• View or click on our ads or other online content; and

• Interact with us through social media websites and other websites and apps. 

In this statement, we also explain how we may combine [Online Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Online Information") with [Other Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Other Information") and how we then use the combined information. 

**What information do we collect online and how do we collect it?**

The types of information we collect depends on which product or service you use.

Sometimes you give information directly to us, our [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners"), or our [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers"). For example, you might give us your name, account number, email, mailing address, phone number, or date of birth when you:

• fill out an online form or survey;

• register, log into or update the settings on your account using our online services;

• register or enroll in our services;

• enter a competition or register for a marketing offer; or

• buy something on our websites or apps.

We (and our [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers") or [Third-Party Ad-Servers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Third-Party Ad-Servers")) also collect information through [Cookies and Similar Technologies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Cookies and Similar Technologies"). Most [Cookies and Similar Technologies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Cookies and Similar Technologies") will only collect [De-Identified Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "De-Identified Information") such as how you arrive at our website or your general location. However, certain [Cookies and Similar Technologies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Cookies and Similar Technologies") do collect [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information"). For example, if you click _Remember Me_ when you log in to our website, a cookie will store your username. 

We (and our [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers") or [Third-Party Ad-Servers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Third-Party Ad-Servers")) may collect information using [Cookies and Similar Technologies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Cookies and Similar Technologies") about:

• the device you use to browse our websites or use our apps (for example, we may collect information about the operating system or the browser version and the type of device you use to open electronic communications from us);

• the [IP Address](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "IP Address") and information related to that [IP Address](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "IP Address") (such as domain information, your internet provider and general geographic location);

• browsing history on our websites or apps (such as what you search for, the pages you view, how long you stay, and how often you come back);

• how you search for our websites or apps, from which website or app you came from, and which of our [Business Partners’](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners’") websites you visit;

• which ads or online content from us and our Business Partners you view, access, or click on;

• whether you open our electronic communications and which parts you click on; and

• the location of your mobile device (for example, to help prevent fraud or when you register to receive location-based content on our mobile websites or apps).

We (and our [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers") or [Third-Party Ad-Servers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Third-Party Ad-Servers")) may also collect information made publicly available through third-party platforms (such as online social media platforms), through online databases or directories, or that is otherwise legitimately obtained. The collection of this information is subject to the third party’s terms of use and/or privacy statement.

 **How do we use the information we collect about you?**

We may use [Online Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Online Information") we collect about you on its own or combine it with [Other Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Other Information") to: 

• deliver products and services, including to:

• recognize you when you return to our websites or use our apps;

• complete transactions; 

• tell you about updates to your accounts, products and services; 

• update you about new features, offers and benefits;

• answer questions and respond to your requests made through our websites or apps and through third-party websites (including social media); 

• use the location of your mobile device for location-based services that you may request;

• determine how to best provide services to you and manage your accounts, such as the best way and time to contact you;

• improve our websites or apps and make them easier to use; 

• advertise and market our products and services – and those of our [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners") – including to:

• present content that is tailored to your interests, including [Targeted Advertising](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Targeted Advertising");

• send or provide you with ads, promotions, and offers;

• analyze whether our ads, promotions, and offers are effective; 

• help us determine whether you may be interested in new products or services; 

• conduct research and analysis, including to:

• better understand our customers and our website or app users;

• allow you to give feedback by rating and reviewing our products and services and those of our [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners"); 

• produce data analytics, statistical research, and reports; 

• review and change our products and services;

• manage fraud and security risk, including to: 

• detect and prevent fraud or criminal activity;

• safeguard the security of your information;

• assess risks relating to our business, including to: 

• evaluate and process your applications for our products and services and manage your existing accounts; and

• use it in other ways as required or permitted by law or with your consent.

 **How do we share your information?**

Some [Online Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Online Information") is [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information"). 

**How we treat your Personal Information**

We do not share [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") with anyone except as described below. We may share [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") as required or as permitted by law, such as:

• with our [Plenti Partners](https://www.plenti.com/partners "Plenti Partners"); (if you do not want us to share your Personal Information with our [Plenti Partners](https://www.plenti.com/partners "Plenti Partners") after you have enrolled, please [click here](https://www.plenti.com/manage-account "click here"))

• with regulatory authorities, courts, and governmental agencies to comply with legal orders, legal or regulatory requirements, and government requests;

• with our [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers"), regulatory authorities, and governmental agencies to detect and prevent fraud or criminal activity, and to protect the rights of Plenti or others;

• within the [American Express Family of Companies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "American Express Family of Companies");

• with our [Service Providers ](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers ")who perform services for us and help us operate our business (we require [Service Providers ](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers ") to safeguard [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") and only use your [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") for the purposes we specify);

• with financial institutions or [Co-brand Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Co-brand Partners") with whom we jointly offer or develop products and services (but they may not use your [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") \- in particular your email address - to independently market their own products or services to you unless you consent that they can do so);

• in the context of a sale of all or part of the [American Express Family](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "American Express Family") of Companies or their assets; or

• for specific products or services, when you have given your consent.

We may transfer [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") to [Service Providers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Service Providers") or companies within the [American Express Family of Companies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "American Express Family of Companies") throughout the world, for example, to process transactions and provide you with our products or services. Regardless of where we process your information, we still protect it in the manner described in this online privacy statement and according to the applicable laws.

 **How we handle[Aggregated Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Aggregated Information") and [De-identified Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "De-identified Information")**

[Aggregated Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Aggregated Information") or [De-identified Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "De-identified Information") does not identify you individually; it helps us to analyze patterns among groups of people. We may share [Aggregated Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Aggregated Information") or [De-identified Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "De-identified Information") in several ways, for example:

• for the same reasons as we might share [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information");

• with [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners") to help develop and market products or services and present targeted content, including [Targeted Advertising](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Targeted Advertising");

• with [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners") to conduct analysis and research about customers, website and app users; or

• with [Third-Party Ad-Servers](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Third-Party Ad-Servers") to place ads (including ads of our [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners")) on various websites and apps, and to analyze the effectiveness of those ads.

 **How do we keep and safeguard your information?**

We use administrative technical and physical security measures to protect your [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information"). These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and facilities. We take reasonable steps to securely destroy or permanently de-identify [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information") when we no longer need it.

We will keep your [Online Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Online Information") only as long as we must to deliver our products and services, unless we are required by law or regulation or for litigation and regulatory investigations to keep it.

 **What are your choices?**

You will always have a right to access, update, and change or correct your [Personal Information](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Personal Information").

You have choices about how Plenti uses your information, such as how we market to you or how we manage [Cookies and Similar Technologies](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Cookies and Similar Technologies"). 

**What are your choices about how we market to you?**

You can choose how you would like to receive marketing communications, including direct marketing - whether we send them to you through postal mail, email, SMS and/or telephone. If you choose to not receive marketing communications from us, we will honor your [choice](https://www.plenti.com/manage-account "choice"). Please be aware that if you choose not to receive such communications, certain offers attached to the products or services you have chosen may be affected. We will still communicate with you in connection with servicing your account, fulfilling your requests, or administering any promotion or any program in which you have elected to participate. 

Please note that the choices you make with Plenti apply to Plenti and do not affect choices that you have made directly with [Business Partners](https://www.plenti.com/onlineprivacystatementglossary "Business Partners"). If you choose to no longer receive marketing communications from one or more of our Business Partners, you must make your choices directly with [them](https://www.plenti.com/partners "them"). 

**We participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) self regulatory program and adhere to the DAA Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.[Click here](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/3686?v=1 "Click here") to learn more about the DAA and your choices.**

 **Do you have questions about the online privacy statement?**

If you have questions about our online privacy statement, call us at 1-885-PLENTI1 (1-855-753-6841), contact us via our online customer service form or email us at [plentiprivacy@aexp.com](mailto:plentiprivacy@aexp.com "plentiprivacy@aexp.com"). 

**Glossary**

 **Aggregated Information** \- data or information relating to multiple people which has been combined or aggregated. Aggregated Information includes information that we create or compile from various sources, including card transactions or certain data from Cookies and Similar Technologies. 

**Plenti (we, our, us),** \- Plenti as identified at the beginning of this online privacy statement. 

**American Express Family of Companies** \- any affiliate and subsidiary of, and any company owned or controlled by, the American Express Company.

 **Business Partners** \- our Plenti Partners or any third parties with whom we conduct business and have a contractual relationship. 

**Co-brand Partners** \- businesses we partner with to offer cards featuring both brand logos. 

**Cookies and Similar Technologies** \- a cookie is a small data file that a website transfers to your computer's hard drive. We may place cookies when you visit our website or another company’s website where our ads appear or when you make purchases, request or personalize information, or register for certain services. If you accept the cookies used on our website, websites that are “powered by” another company on our behalf, or websites where our ads appear, you may give us access to information about your interests. We may use that information to personalize your experience. Similar technologies such as web beacons, pixels, gifs, and tags also do the same thing. We use the term Cookies and Similar Technologies in this statement to refer to all technologies that collect information in this way. 

**De-identified Information** \- data or information used in a way that does not identify you to a third party. We often derive De-Identified Information from Personal Information. It includes information that we may collect from various sources, such as card transactions or certain data from Cookies and Similar Technologies. 

**IP Address** \- a number assigned to a device when connecting to the Internet. 

**Online Information** \- data or information collected on the Plenti’s websites and apps as well as on websites and apps of third parties relating to topics about our business which may include Personal Information, Aggregated Information and De-Identified Information.

 **Other Information** \- Plenti internal information (for example, transaction data), external data that financial and consumer companies use to process applications and complete transactions, and other online and offline information we collect from or about you. 

**Personal Information** \- Information that can identify a person, such as name, address, telephone number, and email address. Personal information includes and may also be referred to as Registration Information. 

**Plenti Partner** \- a company or brand that has an affiliation with Plenti and where Plenti members may earn points and, with certain partners, use points. For a full list of Plenti Partners please click here.

 **Service Providers** \- any vendor, third party and/or company that performs business operations on our behalf, such as printing, mailing, and other communications services (email, direct mail, etc.), marketing, data processing, servicing, collections, or ad management. 

**Targeted Advertising** \- ads we, or our Service Providers, display on websites outside the American Express Family of Companies based on the preferences or interests inferred from data collected from a particular computer or device regarding web viewing behaviors over time and across different websites.

 **Third-Party Ad-Servers** \- companies that provide the technology to place ads on websites (and apps) and track how ads perform. These companies may also place and access cookies on your device. The information they collect from our websites is in a form that does not identify you personally. 

**Web Services** – services which enable authorized websites over the web to connect to Plenti, such as the service which enables linking a member’s Plenti account to a Plenti Partner’s online account.
